<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<helpbook>
	<name>Geotagalog Help</name>
	
	<link href="overview"/>
	<link href="using_tracklogs"/>
	<link href="photo_sources"/>
	<link href="setting_photo_locations"/>
	<link href="export_iphoto"/>
	
	<page id="overview">
		<name>Overview</name>
		<summary>Learn what Geotagalog can do.</summary>
		<content>
			<p>
				Geotagalog lets you <link href="using_tracklogs">open a tracklog</link> and then pick a <link href="photo_sources">source of photos</link>.
				The <link href="setting_photo_locations">photo positions can be fine-tuned</link> along the tracklog using time adjustments.
				The photos may be <link href="photo_preview">previewed in place</link> before <link href="export_iphoto">import into the current iPhoto library</link>.
				</p>
			<p>
				Geotagalog 1.x does not tag photos after they are imported into your iPhoto library.
				For the best workflow, set Geotagalog to launch when you connect a camera, and let Geotagalog import your photos into iPhoto for you.
				</p>
			</content>
		</page>
	
	<page id="about_tracklogs">
		<name>About tracklogs</name>
		<content>
			<p>
				A tracklog is a record of where you have gone. Tracklogs are often gathered by a GPS device or a phone that collects many sample locations in memory as you travel about.
				These sample locations are like pins in a map: the more pins you place, the better they could show the actual route you took.
				</p>
			
			<p>
				For automatic geotagging to work, each sample location should have a timestamp so that Geotagalog can guess where you were when you took each picture.
				If a photo was taken at a time between two location samples, Geotagalog will place the photo at a predicted location using a sophisticated
				interpolation algorithm. (Interpolation is like using a string to fill the gap between pins in a map.)
				</p>
			</content>
		</page>
	
	<page id="using_tracklogs">
		<name>Using tracklogs</name>
		<summary>Getting started with supported tracklog files.</summary>
		<content>
			<p>
				To use Geotagalog, you first need to open a <link href="about_tracklogs">tracklog</link> by clicking the "Open tracklog..." button in the welcome screen.
				Once you have successfully opened a tracklog, Geotagalog will display it on a map so you can use it to geotag photos from a source.
				</p>
			
			<p>
				You may add multiple tracklog files to the map. Simply select multiple tracklogs when opening, use the "File > Open" menu to select another tracklog file,
				or drag tracklog files to Geotagalog's map or Dock icon.
				When prompted, select the "Add Tracks" option. The type of tracklog file does not matter: you can use a GPX file and an NMEA log file on the same map.
				</p>
			
			<p>
				Geotagalog supports tracklogs in several popular formats: the standard GPX format, NMEA 0183 logs, Garmin Training Center (.tcx) files, and FAI Gliding Commission (.igc) flight recordings.
				If your tracking device does not let you directly access tracklogs in one of these formats, you may need to use other software to download and/or convert your tracklogs to a supported format.
				</p>
			</content>
		</page>
	
	<page id="photo_sources">
		<name>Photo sources</name>
		<summary>Picking photos to geotag.</summary>
		<content>
			<p>
				After opening a tracklog, choose a source of photos to geotag using the "Choose photo source..." pull-down button below the map. 
				</p>
			
			<p>
				Geotagalog can geotag photos directly from an attached camera or card reader. Make sure your device is connected, then pick it in the "Choose photo-source..." pull-down menu.
				Using this workflow is the easiest way to GPS-enable your camera.
				</p>
			
			<p>
				Geotagalog can also use individual photos from disk. Click "Choose photo source..." and then pick "Choose files or folders..." in the pull-down menu.
				Geotagalog will load all supported photos you choose, and will search folders and subfolders as well.
				You may also drag photo files and folders directly to Geotagalog's map or Dock icon.
				</p>
			</content>
		</page>
	
	<page id="setting_photo_locations">
		<name>Setting photo locations</name>
		<summary>Ways to change the position of photos on the map.</summary>
		<content>
			<p>
				Geotagalog automatically geotags photos to tracklogs using the timestamps in your photos and in your tracklog. For the most accurate positioning,
				you will need to make sure your camera's time zone and any slight error are set correctly in Geotagalog before importing.
				As you change the camera <link href="setting_camera_time_zone">time zone</link> and <link href="setting_camera_error">error</link> settings,
				Geotagalog will <link href="photo_preview">show a live preview</link> of each photo's location so you check the results.
				</p>
			
			<p>
				If any photos cannot be geolocated well with the provided track data, they may show up in light yellow on the map or disappear from the map completely.
				When this happens, Geotagalog will enable the "Don't geotag when unsure of location" checkbox. You may use this to decide what to do with these photos.
				</p>
			</content>
		</page>
	
	<page id="setting_camera_time_zone">
		<name>Camera time zone setting</name>
		<content>
			<p>
				To set the time zone, use the "Change time zone" button (if necessary) to display the "Camera time zone" configuration.
				If your camera is set to the same time zone as your computer, select the "Same as computer" option.
				</p>
			
			<p>
				If your camera was set to a different time zone, you will need to manually select how many hours the photos' timestamps are offset from Greenwich Mean Time (GMT).
				You may find information about time zone offsets on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_zone">this page</a>.
				</p>
			
			<p>
				(Note: At this time, Geotagalog does not support time zones with non-hour offsets. If your camera's time zone includes a half-hour or quarter-hour offset,
				consider setting your computer to the same time zone, or your camera to a different time zone.
				Otherwise, you must use the fine error correction to add or subtract this non-hour part of the time zone offset.)
				</p>
			</content>
		</page>
	
	<page id="setting_camera_error">
		<name>Camera error</name>
		<content>
			<p>
				Since most tracklog devices have automatically set clocks, Geotagalog assumes that the timestamps in your tracklog are very accurate.
				However, your camera's clock may have been set slightly slow or fast. You may adjust this by pressing the "Change clock error" button (if necessary)
				to display the "Camera clock error" configuration. Move the slider to set what clock error your camera had.
				</p>
				
			<p>
				Geotagalog displays waypoint markers with X symbols on the map. This may be useful when lining up photos taken at known locations.
				Use the <link href="photo_preview">mouseover photo preview</link> to pick the correct photo thumbnail and adjust along the track until
				it is lined up with the matching waypoint marker.
				</p>
			</content>
		</page>
	
	<page id="photo_preview">
		<name>Photo preview</name>
		<content>
			<p>
				Geotagalog displays a live preview of your photos' locations on its map. To view thumbnails of these photos, move your mouse over the map.
				All photos under the mouse cursor will be displayed provided there is room.
				</p>
			</content>
		</page>
	
	<page id="export_iphoto">
		<name>iPhoto import</name>
		<summary>Details about importing into iPhoto.</summary>
		<content>
			<p>
				When your photos look reasonably positioned, press the "Import" button to load them into your current iPhoto library.
				Geotagalog does not modify your original photo files, so iPhoto will always import copies into its library, rather than referencing the original files.
				</p>
			
			<p>
				When photos are not geolocated well with the provided track data, Geotagalog will enable the "Don't geotag when unsure of location" checkbox.
				Use this checkbox to decide whether these photos will be geotagged with the potential poor locations.
				</p>
			
			<p>
				If you decide to not geotag photos with unsure locations, or if your photo source includes non-photo files (such as videos and audio clips),
				Geotagalog can also optionally these into iPhoto, although they will not be geotagged.
				Select the "Include ungeotagged items in import" checkbox to copy non-photo files into your current iPhoto library as part of the import process.
				</p>
			
			<p>
				If you are using an unregistered (demo) version, Geotagalog will only import into iPhoto a limited number of the photos and items.
				To remove this limitation, please <a href="http://calftrail.com/store">purchase a license key</a>.
				</p>
			</content>
		</page>
	</helpbook>